* [
        
        Jun 06, 2024
        
        ### Floods in southern Germany - Allianz donates up to two million euros to rescue and relief services
        
        More](https://www.allianz.com/en/press/news/commitment/community/240606-allianz-donates-up-to-two-million-euros-to-rescue-and-relief-services.html)

    * [
        
        Jun 06, 2024
        
        ### Floods in southern Germany - Allianz donates up to two million euros to rescue and relief services
        
        More](https://www.allianz.com/en/press/news/commitment/community/240606-allianz-donates-up-to-two-million-euros-to-rescue-and-relief-services.html)

    * [
        
        ### Allianz Careers
        
        Learn more about opportunities in Technology and Data at Allianz!
        
        Apply now](https://careers.allianz.com/go/Tech-and-Data-Jobs/9010601/)

    * [
        
        Jun 06, 2024
        
        ### Floods in southern Germany - Allianz donates up to two million euros to rescue and relief services
        
        More](https://www.allianz.com/en/press/news/commitment/community/240606-allianz-donates-up-to-two-million-euros-to-rescue-and-relief-services.html)

    * [
        
        ### SAMEpath
        
        The tool that outlines how the green transition can be achieved within the shrinking timeframe
        
        Go to SAMEpath](https://www.allianz.com/en/economic_research/sustainability-research/samepath.html)

* en

Search Cancel GO

**Privacy Statement**
=====================

* Privacy at Allianz
    
* Privacy notice
    
* Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs)
    
* BCRs companies

Privacy at Allianz

**1\. Introduction**
--------------------

Allianz cares about your personal data. Our mission is to ensure the Allianz’ privacy strategy and framework enable our businesses to maintain the trust of customers, employees and other stakeholders in our handling of personal data. We are committed to the highest standards of data protection and privacy compliance by handling personal data responsibly, transparently, with due care and in a fair and lawful manner. We use it only for specified and legitimate purposes and only keep it for as long as is needed. We never share it with anyone who is not authorized to access it.

We strive to communicate honestly and openly about actions that involve the personal data we process. We integrate data protection into the design of our products (privacy by design) and take appropriate steps to protect personal data and keep it secure

On this page, we would like to introduce you to our Privacy framework and activities.

_"Trust is an integral part of Allianz’s core values. We are committed to maintaining the trust of our employees, customers, and suppliers, and we believe that the protection and ethical use of data is important to achieve this."_

**Barbara Karuth-Zelle**  
Member of the Board  
Allianz SE

**2\. Privacy Principles at Allianz**
-------------------------------------

**Lawfulness, Fairness, and Transparency**; We collect data only for a good reason, for example, if the individual has given their consent or to fulfil a contractual obligation. Individuals are informed in a clear manner how their data will be used.

**Purpose Limitation**; We limit the processing of personal data to only the purposes we’ve communicated to the individual.

**Data Minimisation**; We collect the smallest amount of data that is required to achieve the purposes stated.

**Accuracy**; Correct data is important to us, we have set up verification methods and provided channels for individuals to update their data with us.

**Storage Limitation**; Allianz has a standard for document management with retention schedules. We aim to only keep data for as long as necessary.

**Integrity and Confidentiality**; We take the security of data seriously, implementing technical and organizational security measures to mitigate risks.

**Accountability**; Allianz maintains documentation on how, where, why, personal data is processed to ensure that it can be presented as evidence of our responsibilities to supervisory authorities.

**3\. Privacy Governance at Allianz**
-------------------------------------

The Group Chief Privacy Officer reports directly to a Board Member and is supported by a team of 42 privacy professionals.

128 Privacy FTEs

To ensure compliance throughout the organization, Allianz has 128 Privacy FTEs all over the world.

2,500 Privacy champions

To further embed Privacy principles in the organization, the Privacy function is supported by 2,500 Privacy Champions

**4\. Allianz Sharing of Personal Data**
----------------------------------------

* **Internal:** Allianz has established security rules and controls surrounding the processing of personal data. Only those authorized will be able to process such data.
* **Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs)**: As Allianz is a large multinational company, there needs to be a mechanism to transfer personal data across borders while staying in compliance with EEA data privacy and protection laws and regulations. The Allianz Binding Corporate Rules ("BCRs") provides this mechanism and were approved by the national data protection authorities in the European Economic Area ("EEA"). These authorities include the lead data protection authority for the Allianz Group, the Bavarian Data Protection Authority ("BayLDA"). 
* **External**: For transfers of data outside the Allianz Group, Data Processing Agreements are required to ensure that the recipient has adequate data protection levels and measures in place.

**5\. Data Ethics** 
--------------------

* Allianz strives to conduct data-driven business as a trustworthy and ethical partner to our customers. We have put a range of initiatives in place, such as the 2021 establishment of our Data Advisory Board. With top management represented among its membership, the DAB aims to elevate data ethics and selected data and analytics-related topics in the governance and decision-making processes of Allianz Group.
* Our approach includes implementing a responsible use of Artificial Intelligence (AI) in our business activities, going beyond compliance with all applicable laws and regulations such as the GDPR. We embed best practices by ensuring that our usage of AI systems is human centric.
* Our Allianz Practical Guidance for AI serves as a guide to our core principles for the responsible usage of AI: Transparency, Privacy and Data Governance, Human Agency and Control, Fairness and Non-Discrimination, and Accountability. We take a risk-based approach to implementing the appropriate level of human involvement in each AI use case which processes personal data via the Privacy and Ethics Impact Assessment. All relevant employees who develop or use AI solutions are trained on the Responsible AI approach taken in the Practical Guidance for AI.

**6\. How we ensure Privacy compliance**
----------------------------------------

* Training and awareness
* Privacy by Design and Default
* Records of Processing Activities and Privacy Impact Assessments
* Self-assessments and independent on-site reviews

**7\. Achievements**
--------------------

* Allianz has been ranked in the 100-percentile of the Dow Jones Sustainability Index for three consecutive years, achieving highest possible marks for its privacy protection.  
    
* In its German key market, Allianz has successfully attained the TÜV data protection certification for sale of [Property & Casualty](https://www.tuev-saar.de/zertifikat/tk45019/)\*, [Life\*](https://www.tuev-saar.de/zertifikat/tk45021/) and [Health](https://www.tuev-saar.de/zertifikat/tk45020/) products on [www.allianz.de](http://www.allianz.de/)\*. The TÜV also certified the job applicant process in Germany via [careers.allianz.com](https://careers.allianz.com/).

\* Websites in German

**Some tips to give you even more protection**
----------------------------------------------

**Minimize** the personal data you provide.

**Carefully read privacy notices** and clarify points that are unclear.

**Make your data privacy choices** (opt-in/opt-out) regarding the use of your personal data.

**Use pseudonyms** whenever this is possible.

**Watch out for phishing attempts** (a type of social engineering where an attacker sends a fraudulent message designed to trick a person into revealing sensitive information to the attacker). How you can identify this:

*  check the sender’s e-mail address
*  the overall message, whether there’s any typos or suspicious links

**Keep up-to-date** on privacy developments and news to ensure you know your privacy rights.  

Privacy notice

**We care about your personal data**
------------------------------------

Allianz appreciates your visit to this Allianz group corporate website ("Allianz Website") and your interest in our services and products. Your privacy is important to us and we want you to feel comfortable visiting our site. This privacy notice explains how and what type of personal will be collected, processed and used during and following your visits to the Allianz Website, why it is collected, with whom it is shared and your rights in this regards. Please read this notice carefully.

This privacy notice applies to any information obtained by Allianz through your use of the Allianz Website. It does not apply to any websites controlled by third parties not affiliated with Allianz that the Allianz Website may link to ("Third Party Sites"). Please review the privacy statements of Third Party Sites as Allianz is not responsible for and has no influence on the content or the privacy practices of Third Party Sites.

The terms of this privacy notice are subjected to any additional terms, disclaimers or other contractual terms you have entered into with Allianz such as client privacy statements or notices, and any appliable mandatory laws and regulations. It is important to note that Allianz companies maintain local product-related websites with their own privacy statements about how and what type of personal data will be collected by those Allianz companies and the purposes for which they may collect, share or disclose the data. More information about our Allianz companies can be found [here](https://www.allianz.com/en/about-us/company/contact.html#allianz-worldwide).

This privacy notice may be updated from time to time, please do check it on a regular basis.

**1\. Who is the data controller?**
-----------------------------------

A data controller is the individual or legal person who controls and is responsible to keep and use personal data in paper or electronic files. Allianz SE (Allianz) is the data controller as defined by relevant data protection laws and regulations.

**2\. What personal data will be collected?**
---------------------------------------------

When you visit the Allianz Website, our web server automatically records details about your visit including:

* IP address
* the website from which you visited us
* the type of browser software used
* the Allianz Website pages that you visit
* the date and duration of your visit to the Allianz Website

We will also collect and process various types of personal data, including:

* Surname, First Name, Title
* Address
* Gender
* Contact Details
* Company Name, Business or Profession
* Shareholder Number

**3\. How will we use your personal data?**
-------------------------------------------

Allianz will use your personal data for the following purposes:

* for technical administration, research and development of the Allianz Website
* for customer and user administration and marketing
* to maintain business relationships
* to conduct research and analysis with regard to our business relations
* to inform you about our events, services, products and news when you visit the Allianz Website or when you subscribe to our newsletter or mailing lists
* to facilitate compliance with securities law, public company listing requirements and related laws and regulations
* for fraud prevention and detection
* to comply with any legal obligations (e.g. tax, accounting and administrative obligations)

For the purposes indicated above, we will process personal data we receive about you from public and commercial databases.

We will inform you where we require your consent to process your personal data prior to collection.  Allianz will collect, use and / or disclose your personal data based on consent for the following purposes on this Allianz Website:

* For the use of individual tracking technologies, such as performance or targeting cookies, to develop and improve the services of Allianz, other companies within the Allianz group, business partners and / or other third parties. For more details, please see Sections 4, 5 and 6 below.
* For surveys or newsletter subscriptions to comply with ePrivacy and Competition regulations.

Otherwise, we will process your personal data based on other lawful bases, such as to meet our legitimate business interests (including maintaining contact with clients, providing updates and information about Allianz, organizing and hosting events, and conducting market research and analysis) or where it is needed to comply with a legal obligation. In addition, we may also process your personal data to enter into a contract with you, or to perform our obligations under an existing contract with you.

Allianz respects applicable laws and regulations in its use of personal data.

**4\. Are cookies used on the Allianz website?**
------------------------------------------------

Tracking technology helps us manage and improve the usability of the Allianz Website, for example by detecting whether there has been any contact between your computer and us in the past and to identify the most popular sections of the Allianz Website.

Based on a more detailed description on the usage of cookies our Cookies Management Tool helps you to manage your cookies preferences including providing consent. The link to the respective Cookies Management Tool you find below. You can withdraw   your consent to the usage of certain cookies any time using the before mentioned tool.

When you save your cookie settings, they should also apply to your future visits to the Allianz Website. However, for technical reasons beyond the control of Allianz, this cannot be guaranteed. For example, if you reset your browser, delete your cookies or access the Allianz Website from another browser or device, your cookie settings may be lost. To comply with applicable laws and regulations, in some countries you may be asked to confirm your cookie settings   when you first visit the Allianz Website. If you are in a country where you are automatically required to set your cookie settings, you may be asked to set them again on a future visit.

In many cases you can also control tracking technologies using your browser. Please ensure that your browser setting reflects whether you wish to be warned about and/or accept tracking technologies (such as cookies) where possible. The specific capabilities of your browser and instructions on how to use them can usually be found in the manual or help file of your browser.

Without tracking technologies the availability of the services provided by the Allianz Website may be reduced, or parts of the Allianz Website may no longer function correctly.

**5\. How are social media plug-ins used on the Allianz Website?**
------------------------------------------------------------------

The Allianz Website uses the following social media plug-ins ("plug-ins"):

* Share button and learn more button on Facebook and Instagram, powered by Meta Inc., 1601 S. California Ave., Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA
* Tweet button, powered by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA
* Button Xing, operated by XING AG, Gänsemarkt 43, 20354 Hamburg, Germany
* Share Button on LinkedIn, operated by LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States
* YouTube Plugin, powered by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland
* Learn more on TikTok, by TikTok, 5800 Bristol Pkwy, Culver City, United States

All social media links and plug-ins (YouTube plugin) are indicated with the brand names of the respective providers Facebook, Twitter, Xing, LinkedIn and Google ("Provider"). To increase the level of data protection and in accordance with applicable laws and regulations for plugins, we have implemented additional programs by means of a so-called consent solution. This procedure ensures that when you visit the Allianz Website, no direct connection of your browser to the servers of the Provider is established.

Only if you grant your consent to the data transfer in the cookie consent preferences for the YouTube plugin or by clicking  the direct links for social media, your browser establishes a direct connection to the server of the respective Provider. The Provider receives the information that your browser has accessed the Allianz Website. The content of the plug-in or social media providers is then transmitted by the Providers directly to your browser.

If you interact with the plug-in, e.g. by playing an imbedded YouTube video, the data will be transferred directly from your browser to the Provider and saved by the Provider. 

For more information on the purpose and scope of data collection, processing and use, please refer to the privacy statements below:  

Facebook: [https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/)

Instagram:  [https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy)

Twitter: [https://twitter.com/privacy](https://twitter.com/privacy)

XING AG: [https://www.xing.com/app/share?op=data\_protection](https://www.xing.com/app/share?op=data_protection)

LinkedIn: [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)

Google: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US)

Tiktok: [https://tiktok.com/legal/page/eea/privacy-policy/en](https://tiktok.com/legal/page/eea/privacy-policy/en)

**6\. Who will have access to personal data collected through the Allianz Website?**
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

We will ensure that your personal data is processed in a manner that is compatible with the purposes specified above. For these specified purposes, Allianz may disclose your Personal Data to a third party with your consent or criteria permitted by law. Your personal data may be disclosed to the following parties who operate as third party data controllers:  

* Other Allianz Group companies
* Authorized agents and third party service providers

For the stated purposes, we may also share your personal data with the following parties who operate as data processors under our instruction:

* Other Allianz Group companies
* Authorized agents, service providers, and research analysis agencies
* Facilitators, consultants or experts managing communications and Allianz sponsored events

Finally, we may share your personal data in the following instances:

* With law enforcement agencies, government and regulatory bodies to meet applicable legal or regulatory obligations

**7. Where will collected personal data be processed?**
-------------------------------------------------------

Your personal data may be processed both inside and outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) by the parties specified above, subject always to contractual restrictions regarding confidentiality and security in line with applicable data protection laws and regulations. We will not disclose your personal data to parties who are not authorized to process them.

Whenever we transfer your personal data for processing outside of the EEA by another Allianz company, we will do so on the basis of the binding corporate rules (BCRs) of Allianz which establish adequate protection for personal data and are legally binding on Allianz Group companies. The public version of the BCRs and the list of Allianz Group companies that comply with them can be accessed [here](https://www.allianz.com/en/privacy-statement.html#bcrcompanies).

Where the BCRs do not apply, we will instead take steps to ensure that the transfer of your personal data outside of the EEA receives an adequate level of protection as it does in the EEA. You can find out what safeguards we rely upon for such transfers (for example, Standard Contractual Clauses) by contacting us as detailed below.

**8\. What are your rights in respect of your personal data?**
--------------------------------------------------------------

Where permitted by applicable law or regulation, you have the right to:

* Access your personal data held about you and to learn the origin of the data, the purposes and means of the processing, the details of the data controller(s), the data processor(s) and the parties to whom the data may be disclosed
* Withdraw your consent at any time where your personal data is processed with your consent
* Update and correct your personal data so that it is accurate
* Delete your personal data from our records if it is no longer needed for the purposes indicated above
* Restrict the processing of your personal data in certain circumstances, e.g. where you have contested the accuracy of your personal data, for the period enabling us to verify its accuracy
* Obtain your personal data in an electronic format
* File a complaint with us and/or the relevant data protection authority
* Object to us processing your personal data, or tell us to stop processing it (including for purposes of direct marketing)

### **9\. What security measures have we implemented to protect your information collected through the Allianz Website?**

Allianz has implemented reasonable technical and organizational security measures to protect your personal data collected by Allianz via the Allianz Website against unauthorized access, misuse, loss or destruction.

### **10\. How do we treat electronic messages sent to and from Allianz?**

All electronic messages sent to and from Allianz are protected by reasonable technical and organizational measures and may only be accessed in justified cases in line with applicable laws and regulations (e.g. court order, suspicion of criminal conduct, violation of regulatory obligations) to specific persons in defined functions (e.g. Legal, Compliance, Risk). Every step of the process, as well as the search criteria used, are logged in an audit trail. All emails are disposed of after the applicable retention period has expired.

### **11\. What should you consider when sending data over the Internet?**

The Internet is generally not regarded as a secure environment, and information sent via the Internet (such as to or from the Allianz Website or via electronic message) may be accessed by unauthorized third parties, potentially leading to disclosures, changes in content or technical failures. Even if both sender and receiver are located in the same country, information sent via the Internet may be transmitted across international borders and be forwarded to a country with a lower data protection level than in your country of residence.

Allianz does not accept responsibility or liability for the security of your information whilst in transit over the Internet to Allianz. In order to protect your privacy you may choose another means of communication with Allianz, where you deem it appropriate.

### **12\. How long is personal data retained for?**

We will not retain your personal data for longer than is necessary and we will hold it only for the purposes for which it was obtained.

### **13\. How can you contact us?**

If you have any queries about how we use your personal data, you can contact us by post or email via the details specified below:

Allianz SE  
Group Chief Privacy Officer  
Koeniginstrasse 28  
80802 Munich  
Germany

[\[email protected\]](https://www.allianz.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### **14\. How often is this notice updated?**

We regularly review this privacy notice. We will ensure the most up to date version is published here. This privacy notice was last updated on 2 May 2024.

Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs)

**Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs)**
----------------------------------

The Allianz Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs) provide you with information on the rules governing the international transfer of personal data between Allianz Group companies operating in the European Economic Area (EEA) and Allianz Group companies outside that area.

The BCRs also describe your rights in respect of such transfers, what to do if you want to exercise your rights or complain about such transfers, and how to contact us.

BCRs companies

**BCRs companies**
------------------

Allianz Group companies are required to implement the Allianz Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs). An up-to-date list of Allianz Group companies who have committed to comply with the Allianz BCRs is available here:  

Main pages

Most viewed

We recommend

### Preparing the world for 130 years.

* * *

© Allianz 2024. All Rights Reserved.
